Vijaya Krishna Amrutha Dandamudi

India

Education

M TECH in Information Technology, JNTU University Campus Hyderabad, IN, 2005

B.TECH in Computer Science and Engineering, V.R Siddhartha Engineering College, Vijayawada Nagarjuna University, IN, 2003

Languages

English - Fluent

Telugu - Fluent

Profile

I have 15 years of experience in software product Development using C, C++ , Java languages.

Have around 8 years of expertise in Pattern development used in cloud automation using Chef and Ruby.

Developed multiple chef cookbooks.

Working as VRA/VRO Admin.

Gained expertise in Pattern orchestration using HEAT patterns.

Gained expertise in design and development of products in C, C++ and Java.

Gained expertise in understanding and analyzing the customer requirements for different kinds of products.

Worked closely with the client at onsite location Motorola, SanDiego, USA for the period of 9 months.

Gained knowledge on CIM standard used in the Platform Agent Application.

Had experience in developing mobile applications using Java language on Android and developing BREW UI widgets and multimedia applications.

Gained expertise in writing manual automation and unit test cases.

Involved in improving the code quality.

Key skills

Operating Systems - Linux, windows, Unix

Development Environments - Microsoft Visual Studio, Eclipse

Programming Languages - Chef, SALT, Ruby, HEAT, Python, Java, C, C++, TrigML, Ansible

Revision/Version Control Systems - Clearcase, GIT, Perforce, CMVC

Database - SQLite

Tools - Jira.

Work experience

Lead Engineer - Software

SASKEN COMMUNICATION TECHNOLOGIES LIMITED, India | Feb 2011 - Jan 2013

- 1.Design and development of major product releases
- 2. Fixing bugs in the data link layer.
- 3.Involved in porting the features from one target to another without any issues.
- 4. Handled quality related work.
- 5. Handled the sasken team at the client site.

Module Lead

WIPRO TECHNOLOGIES, India | Mar 2004 - Jan 2011

- 1. Handled the team and taken the task to deliver the releases on time.
- 2.Expertise in design and development of mobiles applications in Java and C/C ++.
- 3. Expertise in understanding and analyzing the customer requirements for different kinds Mobile Applications.
- 4..Bug Fixing.
- 5. Helping the juniors on BREW UI WIDGETS.
- 6.Received FIMC[Feather In My Cap] award from Wipro management for MOTOROLA client project.
- 7. Received appreciations from clients for uiOne customization project.
- 8. Having C level1 and C level2 certifications[Internal to Wipro]

Assignment history

VRA/VRO Admin Role

Kaiser Permanente, India | Mar 2021 - Present

The KP Cloud platform is to build and extend a next generation enterprise automation solution to all the IT operations teams, application services, network, and the emerging world of IoT devices.

Contribution: Maintaining of VRA/VRO, Puppet and Ansible Infrastructure. Troubleshooting the failures in the deployments. Handling the code promotions in the Production environment. Tracking the VRA/VRO, Puppet and Ansible Infrastructure.

CMA ICO & Industrialization, India | Jan 2020 - Dec 2020

The aim of the Industrialization is to allow exploitation of the infrastructure resources in the best cost and time.

This industrialization project focuses on

Reduce the delay to create a new virtual environment (for Poc and production – VM Windows and Linux -AIX LPAR)

Automate and standardize all manual tasks of build processes

Deploy tools to maintain the VM configuration in the time

Contribution: Maintaining of Chef Server and cookbooks in Prod and Test Environment and ICO (IBM Cloud Orchestrator) portal in Test environment.

Troubleshooting and resolving errors related to Chef.

Troubleshooting and resolving ICO related error.

Tracking daily chef server and ICO Portal status.

ASTIR, India | Jul 2019 - Dec 2019

Vodafone Cloud & Hosting Services (VCHS):- Vodafone Cloud and Hosting Services (VCHS) is a part of Vodafone, exclusively servicing and hosting customers (i.e. not Vodafone's internal or Enterprise IT). It is a Service Provider servicing >1000 customers. VCHS is important to Vodafone for its revenue potential.

Contribution: Made changes to multiple chef cookbooks - MQSQL on windows 2016, OS Hardening on windows and linux and CAR cookbooks to incorporate new changes and also to make them as per IBM chef standards.

LLOYDS BANK UK, India | Jan 2017 - Jun 2019

IBM has designed a managed service that offers a Hybrid Cloud that extends into the Bank's existing Traditional IT. The solution will cover both Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) and Platform as a Service (PaaS) for Intel and Linux, enabling the deployment of Cloud-Enabled applications, and a further PaaS, enabling the support of Cloud-Nativeapplications. The solution will include a



service management wrapper that integrates with the overall service management processes and tooling of LBG, spanning the Hybrid Cloud and any other Intel and Unix Traditional IT systems.

Contribution: Setup of chef workstation and chef repository server in the pre-live environment of project.

Developed multiple chef cookbooks- IEM, ITM, Bluecare, Mcafee, Tanium in on both linux and windows operating system and delivered on time.

Developed and owned major patterns like MQ Server and MQ Client on Windows.

Owned windows patterns and handled the version upgrades of agent binaries.

Guided team members on technical queries and doubts

lead a team of developers.

Worked closely with multiple stackholders to get the requirements and resolve the issues.

Complete flow exposure - from requirements understanding to code promotion to Production environment.

Handled the release management in all multiple environments.

ETITHAD, India | Jun 2016 - Oct 2016

Project name: ETITHAD AIRWAYS

ETITHAD AIRWAYS is moving to IBM cloud

Contribution: Developed Chef cookbooks for IEM, TSM and BLUECARE on linux and windows platforms based on the scripts provided.

Developed major patterns like Oracle and MQSQL.

These cookbooks pattern takes care of automating the installation, configuration, verification and starting of the application|service on the remote node|cloud instance.

These chef patterns are used in ICO for deploying software's on cloud instances.

Developed HEAT patterns on softlayer sandpit which helps in migrating and rapidly enabling an existing on-premise core process application/framework on to the cloud

Installing and configuring chef server and repository for binaries

Westpac, India | Jan 2016 - May 2016

Project name: Westpac Speed POC

Westpac client is building a 'digital front door' removing paper & manual



processing, digitised inputs & imaging.

Reduction in storage costs.

Customer Service Hub transition and Strategic Human-Centric Workflow.

First-in-Bank Middleware Patterns developed for use in HPaaS.

Standardized, automated and integrated pattern based deployment.

Increase in deployment efficiency with reduction in deployment timelines and error.

Contribution: Developed 3 individual and 2 integrated (iBPM , FileNet, CMoD, iBPM + FileNet, CMoD + FileNet) ECM patterns on softlayer sandpit which helps in migrating and rapidly enabling an existing on-premise core process application/framework on to the cloud (Genproc - an application build on iBPM and FileNet)

CMoD+FileNet integrated pattern helps in deploying and enabling IBM Content Navigator to perform cross repository search.

16 Chef cookbooks written for these 5 patterns, can be reused for different clients with slight changes as per the new client requests.

Creating Heat Templates for automation

Creating the VMs for the testing the pattern

Maintaining the environment for any overflows like memory and storage

Working very closely with all the other team members to deliver on time

IBM INDIA PRIVATE LIMITED, India | Mar 2014 - Dec 2015

Project name: Rapid Deployment Services

The IBM Pattern Lab employs the Rapid Deployment Service (RDS) re-usable asset based approach to Middleware subsystem delivery.

Rapid Deployment Services (RDS) was developed to automate software product deployment (installation, configuration and integration).

Rapid time to value utilizing automated middleware assets allows drastically decreased time & costs, whilst improving the quality of product and solution deployment.

Contribution: I was part of IBM GTS SSA team.

Developed Chef cookbooks for IBM products as well as 3rd party Products, for eg TSMBAC, .Net, McAfee, ITMA etc based on the requirements that come as

build-sheets.

These cookbooks pattern takes care of automating the installation, configuration, verification and starting of the application|service on the remote node|cloud instance.

These chef patterns are used in ICO for deploying software's on cloud instances.

Documented the developed Cookbooks for IBM and 3rd Party Products.

Staff Software Engineer

IBM INDIA PRIVATE LIMITED, India | Jan 2013 - Feb 2014

Project name: Platform Agent

Platform Agent is well suited for environments that require a smaller footprint without sacrificing a high level of manageability. It provides a subset of Common Agent function used to communicate with and administer the managed systems, including hardware alerts and status information.

Contribution: 1.Design and development of Platform Agent releases.

- 2. Upgrading openssI present in Platform Agent to the newer versions.
- 3. Supporting the new hardware.
- 4. Fixing bugs raised during FVT, BVT and SVT.
- 5.Involved in quality related work.
- 6.To check-in the vendor drops into CMVC.
- 7. Made changes to enable logging in IBM Platform Agent watchdog.
- 8.Made changes to enable tracing in Pegasus.

Lead Engineer - Software

QUALCOMM, India | Feb 2011 - Jan 2013

Project name: QUALCOMM DATAMODEM

Qualcomm Datamodem team handles the data link layer in data modem

Contribution: 1.Design and development of major product releases

- 2. Fixing bugs in the data link layer.
- 3. Involved in porting the features from one target to another without any issues.
- 4. Involved in fixing the Klocwork errors and compiler warnings and errors.
- 5. Writing unit test cases
- 6.Used Qualcomm tools like QPST, QXDM.

7. Handled the sasken team at the client site.

Module Lead

INTEL, India | Apr 2010 - Jan 2011
Project name: INTEL COPORATION

This INTEL COPORATION development project involves design and development of applications on Android

Contribution: 1.Guiding the team in understanding the Android Speech Recognition and SREC Engine Module

- 2. Porting the Android Speed Recogniton and SREC Engine to GoogleTv.
- 3. Developing client for IP Remote service of GoogleTv.

Module Lead

HTC, India | Jan 2010 - Mar 2010 Project name: HTC BMP APPS DEV

This HTC BMP APPS DEV development project involves design and development of touch based commercial handset applications for HTC Corporation. The objective of HTC BMP APPS DEV application development project is to design and develop applications specific to Qualcomm business needs and test it for its endurance. The project also involves system testing and providing support in the customer acceptance of the product.

Contribution: 1. Handled the camera team and taken the task to deliver the releases on time.

- 2.Bug Fixing of camera application.
- 3. Bug fixing of phonecanvas application UI issues.
- 4. Fixing memory leaks in Alarm application.
- 5. Helping the juniors on BREW UI WIDGETS.
- 6.Good understanding of BREW APIs and Interfaces.
- 7. Involved in the system testing of the applications.
- 8. Used Qualcomm tools like QPST, AppLoader, QXDM.

Module Lead

QUALCOMM, India | Feb 2009 - Dec 2009

Project name: QIS BREW APPLICATION MANAGER PRODUCT SUPPORT

This project is to support, enhance and customize the BREW Application Manager application that enables device users to start and manage BREW applications and provides file system support for greater than 4GB capacity. Application Manager also includes a software tool called MobileShop that

allows device users to browse, purchase, and download BREW applications from the BREW Application Download Server(ADS). Every BREW device must implement a version of Application Manager. The project also involves the customization of the BREW Application Manager product based on the OEM/ operator's specific design and branding requirements and supporting them in the maintenance phase.

Contribution: 1.Customization of BREW Application Manager as per Verizon specific design.

- 2.Implemented new feature called ICS smartlink which supports multidownload of BREW applications.
- 3. Fixing the Change Requests raised in the BREW Application Manager
- 4. Performance analysis of the BREW Application Manager.
- 5. Involved in the system testing of the BREW Application Manager.
- 6.Used Qualcomm tools like QPST, AppLoader.

Module Lead

HTC, India | Dec 2008 - Feb 2009

Project name: HTC BMP APPS DEV

This HTC BMP APPS DEV development project involves design and development of touch based commercial handset applications for HTC Corporation. The objective of HTC BMP APPS DEV application development project is to design and develop applications specific to Qualcomm business needs and test it for its endurance. The project also involves system testing and providing support in the customer acceptance of the product

Contribution: 1. Training the juniors on BREW UI WIDGETS.

- 2. Developing BREW customized widgets.
- 3.Involved in the requirements analysis, design and implementation of FMRadio application.
- 4.Involved in the preparation unit test cases, integration and sanity test cases for FMRadio application.
- 5.Involved in the requirements analysis and design of FileManager application.
- 6.Good understanding of BREW APIs and Interfaces.
- 7.Used Qualcomm tools like QPST, AppLoader, QXDM

Module Lead

QUALCOMM, India | Jan 2008 - Nov 2008

Project name: H3G-QIS UIONE CUSTOMIZATION PROJECT

This project is to provide support and customize the uiOne products like mShop

developed by Qualcomm to different carriers. mShop, a Qualcomm product, is a rich, dynamic, and interactive application used for shopping and managing BREW® application purchases. It features a fully updateable and cached storefront to promote applications, a traditional catalog browser with a rich interface, personalized shopping, and a search function to search the catalog. Large parts of mShop can be customized and updated over the air using the uiOne™ SDK TrigBuilder, as well as uiOne Publisher, which can be accessed from TrigBuilder. The project involves understanding the existing design and code of the product and customizes it as per the carrier requirements.

Contribution: 1.H3G_WHITEPHONE- H3G white phone is a low cost BREW device for Pre pay tariffs. Involved in the understanding of the existing mShop product and to customize it to enhance the already provided shopping experience for the new requirements provided by the H3G carrier.

- 2.Involved in the system testing of the mShop product.
- 3.Good understanding of Qualcomm's UDS and ADS and over the air updates.
- 4. Vive Prototyping Developed a prototype in uiOne for the set boxes.
- 5.Used Qualcomm tools like QPST, AppLoader.
- 6. Handled the offshore team for timely deliverables.

Team member

QUALCOMM, India | Jul 2007 - Dec 2007

Project name: QC-QIS-SPRINT-ONDEMAND

The OnDemand product, developed by QUALCOMM, for Sprint PCS is intended to offer a variety of OnDemand content to the user through the use of information channels. Content for each OnDemand channel will be provided by a content server. The OnDemand product consists of a client and server component. The development of client and the UI for the different channels forms the project

Contribution: 1.Involved in the requirements analysis, design and implementation of Update Controller module , which is part of the OnDemand client

- 2.Involved in the requirements analysis, design and implementation of FeedStore module, which is part of the OnDemand client.
- 3. Worked on SQLite for the FeedStore database.

Team member

Motorola, United States | Sept 2006 - Jul 2007

Project name: MOTOROLA_MMA_ONSITE

Motorola CDMA products group is developing a BREW enabled phone. Third party develops the dynamic Multi Media Applications like Camera, Camcorder, Media Player, Sound Recorder, Image Picker and Audio Picker and releases them to Motorola. The Motorola MMA project converts the dynamic mobile

applications to static mobile applications, integrates them with other applications. This project also involves feature testing of Multi Media applications. It also requires designing, developing and implementing new features in the Multi Media.

Contribution: 1.Involved in the requirements analysis, design and implementation of No memory module.

- 2.Bug Fixing of Multimedia applications.
- 3. System and Integration testing of Multimedia applications.
- 4. Target debugging using JTAG and Trace32.
- 5. Worked directly with the Motorola client at San Diego.
- 6.Received "Feature in my Map" award for the contribution to the project.
- 7.Used Qualcomm tools like QPST, QXDM.

Team member

QUALCOMM, India | Apr 2004 - Aug 2006

Project name: SIRIUS-QCT UI DEVELOPMENT

Sirius 3G-UI application development project involves design and development of commercial 3G UMTS mobile handset applications for Qualcomm. The objective of Sirius 3G-UI application development project is to design and develop applications specific to Qualcomm business needs and test it for its endurance. The project also involves integration testing and providing support in the customer acceptance of the product.

Contribution: 1.Involved in the requirements analysis, design and implementation of Currency Converter application.

- 2. Involved in preparation of unit test cases, integration and sanity test cases for Currency Converter application.
- 3.Involved in the requirements analysis, design and implementation of FMRadio application.
- 4. Taken responsibilities for all the deliverables of FMRadio application.
- 5.Involved in the maintenance of Currency Converter and FMRadio application.
- 6. Involved in Bug Fixing of FMRadio application.
- 7. Involved in adaptation of Thumbnail feature in Mplayer application.
- 8. Involved in Target debugging using JTAG and Trace32.
- 9.Involved in writing BREW APIs and Interfaces for applications.
- 10. Involved in training sessions for BREW.

11.Involved in System testing and Integration testing.

